开萝尔∶妈妈,爸爸.
Carol: Hi mom.Hi dad.
杰森∶嗨!
Jason: Hey.
开萝尔∶再见.
Carol: See ya.
杰森∶嗨!等等,你要去哪里 ?
Jason: Hey wait a minute, where are you going?
开萝尔∶去上班.
Carol: Work.
麦琪∶这么早吗?
Maggie: This early?
开萝尔∶我跟我老板保证过,要早点到,
Carol: Well, I promised my boss I would come in early so I could get off
这样,4点钟的时候我就可以去哥伦比亚大学进行新生适应.
by 4 to make my freshman orientation at Columbia.
杰森∶哦!是今天吗?
Jason: Oh, is that today?
开萝尔∶没错,是不是很让人兴奋?好了,我要走了.
Carol: Yeah, isn't that exciting? Well, I gotta go.
麦琪∶宝贝,我还记得当哥伦比亚上个学期拒绝你的时候,
Maggie: Oh, honey, I remember how devastated you were when Columbia didn't
你是多么的沮丧呢.
have room for you last semester.
开萝尔∶对,最后...
Carol: Yeah, well finally...
杰森∶我还记得我说过"开萝尔,你为何不利用这段空闲时间去找份工作呢?"想不到,新的学期在不知不觉中就来临了.
Jason: Yeah, I believe I said "Carol, why don't you use the downtime to take
a job?" The next semester will be around before you know it
开萝尔∶我真的很喜欢工作.
Carol: I've actually enjoyed working.
杰森∶这也是我意料之中的.
Jason: Which I believe I've also predicted.
开萝尔∶现在是我上哥伦比亚大学大学的时候了,我已经准备好了.
Carol: Well, it's time for Columbia university and I am ready.
杰森∶是,是,我早就知道她一定能行.
Jason: Yep, yep, yep. Which is what exactly I knew she would...right.
斯他峰格尔先生∶西维尔,你在这里干什么?
Mr.Staffengero: Seaver, what are you doing here?
Carol: Mr.Staffengero, don't you remember that I said I'd come in early
斯他峰格尔先生∶没有人打电话给你?
Mr.Staffengero: You mean nobody called you? staffengero
开萝尔:是什么?
Carol: About what?
斯他峰格尔先生∶你已经不再这里工作了.
Mr.Staffengero: You don't work here anymore. staffengero
开萝尔∶什么?但是我是这个部门最好的分页职员.
Carol: What? But I'm the best page break clerk in the department.
斯他峰格尔先生∶不用了.在你离开前,我有一些事情要和你说.
Mr.Staffengero: Not anymore. And before you go I'd like to say a few things.staffengero
开萝尔∶我也有一些事情要和你说.
Carol: Well, there are a few things I'd like to say too.
你不是一个很好的老板.
You are not a very good boss.
斯他峰格尔先生∶什么?
Mr.Staffengero: What?
开萝尔∶应该有人告诉你,
Carol: And somebody should tell you this because it might do you some good.
因为这是为你好.你有狐臭.
You have major "BO" [body odor].
我不是因为被开除才这样说的.
And I'm not saying that because I'm getting fired.
斯他峰格尔先生∶你不是被开除,你是被提升了.
Mr.Staffengero: You're not being fired, you're being promoted.
开萝尔∶你没有一个人在电梯里呆过吗?说什么?
Carol: Have you been alone with yourself in an elevator? Pardon me?
斯他峰格尔先生∶那些标点部门的废物在得知你是多么的优秀后,
Mr.Staffengero: Those punks in punctuation heard how good you are and
决定把你偷到他们部门去当经理.
they are stealing you to be their manager.
开萝尔∶要我当经理?
Carol: I'm a manager?
斯他峰格尔先生∶你知道是谁告诉他们关于你的所有的优点的吗?
Mr.Staffengero: And do you know who told them all those good things about you?
是你的有狐臭的前老板---我.
Your smelly ex-boss, that's who.
开萝尔∶恩,你其实没有那么臭.
Carol: Well, you don't smell that bad.
开萝尔∶哈罗!
Carol: Hello.
秘书∶不要再浪费我的时间了.我需要更多的方案.我的新经理马上就要来了,我必须把他的办公室弄的完美无缺.我决不会给他任何解雇我的借口,而把与他有私通的秘书带来.
Secretary: Don't put me on hold again.I need more plans.My new manager is due here any second and his office has got to be perfect.I don't want to give him any excuses to fire me and bringing his own secretary, who he's probably having an affair with.
开萝尔∶对不起,我想我就是你的新经理.
Carol: Excuse me I think I'm your new manager.
秘书∶你是西维尔先生?
Secretary: You're Mr.Seaver?
开萝尔∶我是!
Carol: I am.
秘书∶有没有对你的老板说过会让你觉得后悔的话?
Secretary: Ever said anything to your boss that you've regretted?
开萝尔∶刚刚,还说他有狐臭来着.
Carol: Just, that he smelled bad.
秘书∶哦!你是斯他峰格尔先生的手下.
Secretary: Oh, you worked for Mr.Staffengero.
开萝尔∶哪个办公桌是我的?
Carol: So, which desk is mine?
秘书∶你开什么玩笑?你的办公室就在那里.
Secretary: Are you kidding?Your office is right over there.
开萝尔∶我有一个办公室?
Carol: I have an office?
秘书∶是的,西维尔小姐.
Secretary: Yes, Ms.Seaver.
开萝尔∶叫我开萝尔就好了.
Carol: Ah, please call me Carol.
秘书∶你好,我是你的秘书乐斯莉.
Secretary: Hi, I'm Leslie your secretary.
开萝尔∶哦,真对不起,
Carol: Oh, I'm sorry but I have my own secretary.
我已经有了我自己的秘书.他正在健身房健身呢.我开玩笑的.
He's pumping up at the gym today.I'm kidding.
秘书∶哦哇,一个有幽默感的老板.
Secretary: Oh wow, a boss with a sense of humor.
开萝尔∶这是我的办公室?
Carol: This is my office?
秘书∶啊...我以为会是男士.因为我们这里的经理大都是男士.
Secretary: Uh huh.You know, I expected a guy.They are always guys.
开萝尔∶真的?
Carol: Really?
秘书∶是的.
Secretary: Yeah.And none of them ever asked me to call them by their first
并且他们当中没有一个人让我直呼其名.除了有一次在圣诞晚会的复印机上.
name.Except once at a Christmas party, on the Xerox machine.
如果你需要我尽管给我电话.
If you need me just phone.
开萝尔∶我首先做什么呢?熟悉我的新职位?
Carol: What should I do first?Should I learn my new job?
还是打电话给迈克炫耀一下?
Or call Mike and gloat?
本∶我只是问问如果我的成绩又好,
Ben: I'm just asking if my grades stay up and if Gary's parents say it's
加里的父母也答应,我也保证听伴护的话,
okay and if I promise to obey the chaperon,
你还会反对我去参加周末滑雪吗?
would you have any objections to me going on a ski weekend?
麦琪∶哦,你爸爸怎么说?
Maggie: Oh, what's your father say?
本∶他不会有问题的.
Ben: He has no problems with it.
麦琪∶你问你爸爸了吗?
Maggie: Did you ask your father?
本∶他不会有问题的.
Ben: He has no problems with it.
麦琪∶因此,你没有问过你爸爸了?
Maggie: So, you didn't ask your father?
本∶我认为只要征得妈妈的同意,爸爸也就不会有什么意见了.
Ben: Well, I kind of figured that I start at the top and work my way down.
麦琪∶好吧.
Maggie: Ok.
杰森∶你好本.你好克莉丝.
Jason: Hi Ben.Hi Christy.
本∶爸爸,你记不记得你说过,如果妈妈同意我去参加滑雪旅行的话,你也就没有什么问题了,
Ben: Dad, you remember that ski trip that you said I could go on if mom
对吗?妈妈刚才说答应了.
Jason: Hi sweetheart.杰森∶你好宝贝.
said it was okay?She said okay.Yes.
麦琪∶你好.我刚才被一个13的小孩子给哄骗了.
Maggie: Hi.I've just been outsmarted by a 13 year old.
杰森∶我也被他哄骗过.
Jason: Well he got me too.
当他注视着你说"只要妈妈同意了,你也就同意了"的时候,
It's tough to resist the little tyke when he looks at you and says "I'm
你真的很难去拒绝这个小淘气.
starting at the top and working my way down."
麦琪∶本.不要这么早就给滑雪板打蜡.
Maggie: Ben.Don't start waxing those skis yet, young man.
迈克∶大家好!嗨!
Mike: Hi guys.Hey mom.
妈妈.
Listen I have a paper due tomorrow so I'm going to get some dinner at
因为我明天有一场考试,所以你能不能帮我把晚餐拿到楼上我房间?
take it up to our place, okay?
麦琪∶去吧,去吧.
Maggie: Fine.Go ahead.
剥夺了一天中我唯一一次可以享受全家人团聚的机会.
Deprive me the single chance I have everyday to enjoy the oneness of my brood.
迈克∶好了.
Mike: Ok.
本∶但是我已经告诉大家我要去的.
Ben: But I told everybody I was going.
麦琪∶什么时候说的?
Maggie: When?
本:昨天.
Ben: Yesterday.
开萝尔∶你们决不会相信今天在工作上发生了什么事.
Carol: You never believe what happened at work today.
本∶开萝尔,我们正在讨论一件很重要的事情.
Ben: Carol, we're in the middle of something very important here.
.杰森∶不,我们没有.我们已经说完了.
Jason: No, we're not.We are at the end of it
开萝尔∶我升职了.我现在是标点部门的经理了.
Carol: I got a promotion.I'm the manager of the punctuation department.
麦琪∶哦!宝贝儿,太好了!
Maggie: Oh honey, that's wonderful.
杰森∶没错.当你告诉他们你不能接受升职的时候,
Jason: Yes.So Carol were they disappointed at work when you told them
他们是不是感到很失望,开萝尔?
you couldn't accept the promotion?
开萝尔∶我为什么要告诉他们那些?
Carol: Why would I tell them that?
杰森∶因为2个星期后你就要去哥伦比亚大学上学了.
Jason: Because you're starting Columbia university in two weeks.
开萝尔∶对,对.
Carol: Right, right.
麦琪∶新生适应感觉怎么样?
Maggie: How was the freshman orientation?
开萝尔∶是今天,对吗?
Carol: That was today wasn't it?
杰森∶你没有去?
Jason: You didn't go?
开萝尔∶我完全忘记了.
Carol: I completely forgot.
本∶我也忘记了.你说我能去还是不能去?
Ben: I forgot too.Did you say I could or couldn't go?
开萝尔∶好我会赶上下一个适应.
Carol: Well I'll just catch my next orientation.
我会让秘书帮我写在日程表上.
I'll just have my secretary put it on my calendar.
麦琪∶你有一个秘书?
Maggie: You have a secretary?
开萝尔∶哼哼.
Carol: Uh hum.
本∶她有责任承担滑雪旅行的全部费用.
Ben: And she owes it all to ski trips.
开萝尔∶好了.哲学,人类学,微积分学,
Carol: Ok.Philosophy, anthropology, calculus, political science,
政治学,英国文学,法语和德语.星期二…
English literature, French and German.Now for Tuesday...
迈克∶嗨!
Mike: Hey Carol, listen,
开萝尔,我明天要把这篇论文交上去,
I have this paper due tomorrow and I wonder if you can look it over for
不知道你能不能帮我把它看一遍?
me?
开萝尔∶多少钱?
Carol: How much?
迈克∶哦!,打心底里.
Mike: Oh, from the bottom of my heart.
开萝尔∶不行.你到底打算付我多少钱?
Carol: No.How much are you going to pay me?
迈克∶付钱给你?别提了.
Mike: Pay you?Forget it.
开萝尔:迈克,我马上去洗手.
Carol: Carol: Mike, I'll be washing my hair.
你等的时间越长,给你越多啊.
Every minute you wait, the price goes up.
Mike: Yeah, who needs your help? I'm perfectly happy with a D.Hello
好的,稍等.开萝尔,找你的.是个男的.
Okay, just a minute. Carol, for you. Some guy.
开萝尔∶你以为我会相信你?
Carol: You expect me to fall for that?
迈克∶很对不起.她不认识任何的男士.
Mike: I'm sorry.She doesn't know any guys.
她现在无法接听你的电话.如果你一定要知道的话,
Well, she can't come to the phone right now.
那我就告诉你,她在洗澡.
If you must know, she's in the can.
开萝尔∶真地有人打电话找我?
Carol: Is there really somebody on the phone?
迈克∶当然.他说是你公司的.他说有很紧急的事情要找你.
Mike: Yeah, oh yeah.He says he's from your work.He says it's an emergency.
开萝尔∶不可能的.
Carol: Well that's impossible.
迈克∶你想她从位子上爬下来接你电话吗?
Mike: You expect her to climb off the throne for that?
开萝尔∶哈罗.我是开萝尔西维尔.比尔,
Carol: Hello.This is Carol Seaver.Bill, sure I remember you.
我当然记得你.不,你没有妨碍我的事情.
No, you didn't pull me away from anything.I have to approve the text?
我必须要同意那个文本?但是我才当了一天的经理而已.
But I've only been the manager for one day.Uh huh.
哼哼.我想在我没有核对最后的草稿前,我应该说不,
Well I guess if I didn't check the final draft I should say no, right?
对吗?好的,再见.
Ok.Bye.
开萝尔∶迈克,今天晚上要启动一个5万美金的印刷经营,
Carol: Mike.A $50,000 press run was set off to start tonight,
但是他们要征得我的口头同意才行.
but they needed my verbal okay.
迈克∶哦哇,5万美金的印刷经营?
Mike: Oh wow, a $50,000 press run?
开萝尔∶对.
Carol: Yes.
迈克∶哦,天啦,我还不知道他们那还印刷钱呢.
Mike: Oh man, I didn't know they printed money there.
开萝尔∶出去!
Carol: Get out.
迈克∶啊?我说什么了?
Mike: What did I say?
开萝尔∶出去!
Carol: Out.
麦琪∶哈!?哦,哦.
Maggie: Huh?Oh.Oh.
杰森∶我有告诉过你那本书很不错吗?
Jason: Did I tell you that it was a great book or what?
麦琪∶我只是随便翻了翻,就没法再放下了.
Maggie: I'm turning the pages and I can't put it down.
Jason: Did you get to the part yet where they found out that Mr
而他事实上就是那个凶暴的人?
Shepard is just an Alias and he's really the dragon?
麦琪∶他就是凶暴的人?
Maggie: He's the dragon?
杰森∶哦,宝贝儿对不起.
Jason: Oh.Ah honey I'm sorry.
麦琪∶不,本.我们未曾改变我们的决定.不能去滑雪旅行.
Maggie: No Ben, we haven't changed our minds.No ski trip.
开萝尔∶我有打扰你们吗?
Carol: Am I interrupting something?
麦琪∶今晚没有.
Maggie: Not tonight.
开萝尔∶我想跟你们谈谈我辞职的时间.
Carol: Well I want to talk to you about the right time to quit my job.
麦琪∶宝贝儿,按照惯例,你要提前2个星期提出来.
Maggie: Well honey it's customary to give about two weeks notice.
开萝尔∶我不是这个意思.我认为我还不想辞职.
Carol: That's not what I meant.I don't think I want to quit.
麦琪∶哦!
Maggie: Oh wait a minute.
等一下.
Is this going to end up with you asking me if Ben can go on a
你刚才是不是在问我本到底能不能去滑雪旅行呀?
ski trip?
开萝尔∶妈妈.我是认真的.这个学期,我不想去上哥伦比亚.
Carol: Mom.I'm serious.I don't want to go to Columbia next semester.
麦琪∶不去哥伦比亚?你在开什么玩笑,
Maggie: Not go to Columbia?
你成绩那么好,还有你的奖学金和你的梦想.
You're kidding; with your grades and your scholarship and your dreams.
杰森∶停,亲爱的,不要插话,让她说完.
Jason: Hold on, honey, don't go off half-cocked here.Let her finish.
吉∶好,我不会插话了.
Maggie: Fine.I'll go off half-cocked then.
开萝尔∶我只是在想.
Carol: See, I was thinking.
麦琪∶想?你怎么会有这样的想法?哈!
Maggie: Thinking?And where do you get this behavior, huh?
开萝尔∶妈妈,如果你不介意的话,
Carol: Mom, if you don't mind I'd like to talk this out with someone who's
我想和有理性的人谈谈.没有攻击.
rational.No offense.
麦琪∶你爸爸能明白.杰森,让我走.
Maggie: Your father understands.Jason will you give us a minute?OH.
开萝尔∶你不必离开,只要不说话就好了.
Carol: Well you don't have to leave, just don't say anything.
麦琪∶好吧,我就只看书.
Maggie: Fine.I'll just read a book.
开萝尔∶我明白这只是一份临时的工作,是你的主意,
Carol: Well, I know this was only supposed to be a temporary job,
谢谢你.
which was your idea and thank you.
杰森∶不用谢.
Jason: You're welcome.
开萝尔∶升职后,我会花更多的时间在工作上,
Carol: But with this promotion I'll get more time in the work force,
这些你也说是个好主意,再次谢谢你.
which you've said was a good idea, and again thank you.
杰森∶不用谢.
Jason: You're welcome.
开萝尔∶只不过是一个学期,
Carol: But it'll only be for one more semester and Columbia will be waiting
哥伦比亚大学在秋季学期仍然会接受我的.
for me in the fall.
因此我不知道要怎样来拒绝你的合理解释
So I don't see how a reasonable person like yourself could object.
杰森∶谢谢你.
Jason: Thank you.
开萝尔∶不用谢.
Carol: You're welcome.
杰森∶开萝尔,
Jason: Well, Carol I know that getting a promotion and being entrusted
我明白得到提升以及被委以重任是一件多么重要的事情.
with all this responsibility is pretty heavy stuff.
开萝尔∶是的.
Carol: It is.
杰森∶我我相信你已经问过你自己这样的问题了,
Jason: Now I'm sure you've asked yourself this,
新职位真的值得推迟12年来的所有准备吗?
is this new job really worth putting 12 years of preparation on hold?
开萝尔∶恩...
Carol: Well...
杰森∶因为很多人,一旦他们迷失了自己的目标,
Jason: Because a lot of people, you know,
就很难再次重拾信心....
once they lose sight of their goals they never quite get a fix on them again.
开萝尔∶你认为我现在正在这样做吗?
Carol: You think that's what I'm doing?
杰森∶你有吗?
Jason: Do you?
开萝尔∶或许.
Carol: Maybe.
杰森∶宝贝,是你自己的人生,
Jason: Well, sweetheart it's your life and you got to make your own decisions
你必须自己做决定,选择自己的路.只是我不愿意看到你失去上大学的动力.
and call your own shots.I just hate to see you lose your momentum for college.
开萝尔∶你说得对,明天我就去辞职.
Carol: You're right, I'll give my notice tomorrow.
杰森∶不,不.除非你想.
Jason: Hey, no, no.Only if you want to.
开萝尔∶我是真的想.爸爸谢谢.妈妈,谢谢你没有发表意见.
Carol: I do.Thanks daddy.And thanks mom for not saying anything.
杰森∶只是一个阶段而已,有时他们想和妈妈谈,
Jason: It's just a phase,
有时呢,
sometimes they want to talk to the mom and sometimes they want to talk
就会想和爸爸谈.让我们感激她愿意和我们谈.
to the dad.Let's just be thankful she's just talking.
麦琪∶杰森,钟表工人是这样做的.
Maggie: Jason, the watchmaker did it.
乐斯莉∶早安开萝尔.
Leslie: Good morning Carol.
开萝尔∶乐斯莉,谁是我的老板?
Carol: Leslie, who's my boss?
Leslie: All department managers report to Mr.Littlefield
开萝尔∶你能不能告诉他我要立刻见他?
Carol: Well could you tell him that I have to see him right away?
乐斯莉∶可能要等几个星期.
Leslie: It'll take weeks.
开萝尔∶我不能等.我在2个星期内要去哥伦比亚.
Carol: Well I can't wait.I'm going to Columbia in two weeks.
乐斯莉∶你认为你丢下这里的一切明智吗?
Leslie: You think that's wise with all that whole drugs thing going on down here?
开萝尔:你别说那么多了,只管打电话给他.
Carol: Could you just call him?
光线∶早上好.我把印刷经营延迟到下个星期了.
Ray: Morning.I have the press run deadlines done for next week.
开萝尔∶哦!谢谢瑞.
Carol: Oh, thanks Ray.
瑞∶当然.
Ray: Sure.
开萝尔∶等等.Littlefield先生是怎么样的一个人?
Carol: Wait.What kind of a guy is Mr.Littlefield?
瑞∶副总?哦!他是一个不错的人.
Ray: The VP?Oh, he's a great guy.
开萝尔∶啊?你怎么知道他的?
Carol: Yeah?Well how do you know him?
光线∶去年我们损失惨重,他接下我们的部门,
Ray: Last year we had a major screw-up and he came down and he reamed
然后对我们其中的一半进行整顿,解雇了另一半.
half of us and fired the other half.
开萝尔∶那他怎么还是一个不错的人呢?
Carol: So how's he a great guy?
瑞∶我还在这里.
Ray: I'm still here.
乐斯莉∶Littlefield先生今天不但要见你,
Leslie: Not only is Mr.
并且他正在来这里的路上.
Littlefield going to see you today, he's coming here now.
开萝尔:是么?开玩笑吧.
Carol: He is?You're kidding.
乐斯莉∶你比我想像中的还要重要.
Leslie: You're more important than I thought.
Littlefield先生:伙计们,坚持.你是开萝尔?
Mr.Littlefield: Carry on, troops.You're Carol Seaver?
开萝尔∶是的;littlefield先生.
Carol: Yeah, Mr.Littlefield.
Littlefield先生:好,好.我是沃伦.
Mr.Littlefield: Please, please.I'm Warren.
开萝尔∶我没想到你会专程来见我.
Carol: I didn't expect you to come down here to see me.
Mr.Littlefield: Nonsense, I wanted to come down and welcome you board
Littlefield我昨天本来要来的但是有事情.对了,
yesterday but got tied up.Not literally, of course.
Littlefield昨天晚上的电话不错.
Hey, that was a great call last night.
开萝尔∶不错的电话?
Carol: Great call?
Mr.Littlefield: You saved us 50 grand by stopping that press run
Littlefield你做得好.
The copy was not ready and you made the right decision.
开萝尔∶谢谢.
Carol: Well, thank you.
Littlefield先生:我会关注你的.
Mr.Littlefield: I got my eye on you Carol.
Littlefield这里是你成功的起点.
This is just the start of big things for you here.
开萝尔∶真的?
Carol: Really?
Mr.Littlefield: Now, what was that urgent matter you wanted to talk with
me about?
开萝尔∶我,
Carol: Well, see I, ah, well,
这是我的人生,我要自己选择路去走,
this is my life and I have got to call my own shots and I am
我不会辞职了.
not quiting.
先生∶你不会了?
Mr.Littlefield: You're not?littlefield
开萝尔∶不会.
Carol: No.
Mr.Littlefield: Oh.Well this has been a productive meeting
开萝尔∶不要盯着我.
Carol: Don't stare at me.
本∶其他的小孩子都要去滑雪.
Ben: All the other kids are going to go skiing.
杰森∶我们不是其他小孩的父母.我们是你的父母.
Jason: Well we're not all the other kids' parents.We're yours.
迈克∶本,你告诉过他们热槽了吗?
Mike: Benny, did you tell them about the hot tub?
本∶一切就绪啦.加里的哥哥正好从海军回来休假,他会一直看着我们的.
Ben: Everything's going to be cool.Gary's older brother is home on leave from the navy and he's going to be watching us the whole time.
麦琪∶19岁的海员不能算是好的伴护.
Maggie: A 19 year old sailor is not my idea of a chaperon.
本∶女孩子们肯定会认为我是胆小鬼.
Ben: [But the girls are going to think] I'm a total weenie.
杰森∶女孩子们也去?你太让我震惊了?
Jason: Girls are going too?Are you too as shocked as I am?
麦琪∶嗨,宝贝儿怎么样?
Maggie: Hi, honey.How're you?
开萝尔∶爸爸,你说得对.是我的人生,我要自己选择自己的路.
Carol: Dad, you're right.It's my life and I have to call my own shots.
因此,我听你的建议,决定不辞职了.谢谢你.
So I'm taking your advice, I'm keeping my job.Thank you.
麦琪∶开萝尔,等等.
Maggie: Carol.Hold on one minute, young lady.
杰森∶别动.
Jason: Stay.
麦琪∶宝贝,你不能换一个吗?
Maggie: Carol, don't you take another step.
杰森∶我们昨天晚上不是已经谈过这件事情了吗?
Jason: I thought we covered this matter last night?
麦琪∶杰森如果你要开始讲道理的话,
Maggie: Jason if you start reasoning again I swear I am going to go on
我发誓我会去处理与19岁的海员一起参加的滑雪旅行.
that ski trip with the 19 year old sailor.
开萝尔∶妈妈,你认为这不是我应该要做的决定吗?
Carol: Mom, don't you understand that this was my decision to make?
杰森∶开萝尔,也许我们昨天晚上的交流出现了一点点误会.
Jason: Well maybe we've mis-communicated last night, Carol.
开萝尔∶完全没有,那你有没有说这是我自己的人生?
Carol: Not at all, did you or did you not say this is my life?
杰森∶说过.
Jason: Yes.
开萝尔∶那你有没有说我必须自己选择自己的路吗?
Carol: And did you or did you not say that I have to call my own shots?
杰森∶说过.
Jason: Well yes.
开萝尔∶那你有没有说...
Carol: And did you or did you not say...
杰森∶那你有没有说过你要去上哥伦比亚大学,
Jason: Did you or did you not say you were going to Columbia and quitting
辞掉那份工作的?
this job?
麦琪∶我们知道那可不是我说的.
Maggie: Well we know it wasn't me.
开萝尔∶我以为你会相信我的判定.
Carol: I thought you trusted my judgement.
杰森∶我相信.既然那些都没有起到作用,
Jason: So did I.
我觉得我有必要跟你说清楚,
But since that didn't work I'm going to lay it out for you Carol.
开萝尔.你不能因为愚蠢的工作而放弃你12年来所做的准备.
You're not dumping 12 years of preparation over some goofy job.
开萝尔∶愚蠢的工作?
Carol: Goofy job?
杰森∶麦琪,你看,我们还指望她呢...
Jason: Come on, Maggie, we've been counting on her.
I mean, straight A's, class valedictorian, full scholarship to Columbia
全额的奖学金去上哥伦比亚大学.只要我活着,她就不能放弃这个机会.
And she's not going to throw it all down the drain, no over my dead body.
麦琪∶哦!杰森你也是不讲理的∶我爱你.
Maggie: Oh Jason you're not reasonable: I love you.
杰森∶谢谢.理智只是表面,我内心是和你一样的.
Jason: Thank you.Reason is my cover, inside I'm as wacko as you.
麦琪∶杰森,我从来都没见过你这样.
Maggie: Jason, I have never seen you like this.
杰森∶麦琪,我该怎么做?
Jason: What am I going to do, Maggie?
我一直对自己没能上哥伦比亚大学而艮艮于怀.我是说如果我们不能,
I mean I'm never going to forgive myself if I don't graduate from Columbia.
如果她也不能,如果她的.
I mean if we don't, if she don't graduate, if her.
不管怎么说,你明白我的意思.
Aw, you know what I mean.
麦琪∶我上去和她好好谈谈.
Maggie: I'll go up and talk to her.
本∶爸爸.关于滑雪旅行的事情,我感觉我也必须选择自己的路,因此...
Ben: Dad.About this ski trip deal, I feel that I have to call my own shots here so...
杰森∶出去,出去,出去,出去.
Jason: Out, out, out, out.
开萝尔∶很高兴你能来.这是我的哥伦比亚课程目录.
Carol: Oh, I'm glad you're here.Here's my Columbia course catalogue.
请帮我选择我的班级.我可不想有什么误会.那儿有
Please pick out my classes.I want to make sure there's no mis-communication.
麦琪∶开萝尔,你可以自己选择班级.
Maggie: Carol, you can pick out your own classes.
开萝尔∶哦!我不知道自己是否有资格.
Carol: Oh gee, I don't know if I'm up to that.
麦琪∶开萝尔,我希望你的态度好点.
Maggie: Carol, I'd like a better attitude than this.
开萝尔∶随便你选.
Carol: Whatever you want.
麦琪∶如果你觉得我们可以毫无异议的接受你人生方向的改变,那你是太高估我们了.
Maggie: Look, Carol I think you're expecting too much from of us if you
现在,你说只是暂时的,
think we'll accept a major change in your life's direction without an
但是,我们怎么能保证呢?
argument.Now, I know you say it's only temporary, honey.
如果我们的期望对你来说是一种负担,
But how can we be sure?
那我们真的非常抱歉,但是,
I'm sorry if our expectations are a burden,
这种期望也是你自己选择的,自从你5岁就开始读书开始.
but you brought that on yourself when you started reading at the age of five.
开萝尔∶4岁半.
Carol: 4 ?.
麦琪∶只是我们私下说说,如果你什么时候重复给别人听的话,
Maggie: Yeah?You know, honey,
我都不会承认的.你知道吗?
just between us and if you ever repeat this I'll deny it.
你有一种你的弟弟们都没有的天赋.
You have a gift that, frankly, your brothers don't have.
你那么能干,有那么多的机会.
There's so much you could do; you have so many opportunities.
开萝尔∶妈妈,很多人要向我汇报.我在管理一个部门.
Carol: Mom, people are reporting to me.I'm running a department.
以前都没有这样过.我是说,我第一个月上班的时候,
I've never had that.I mean, my first month there my hands shook everyday.
我的双手每天都发抖.而现在呢,员工来见矮小的我,
And now people come to see me, little me, their hands shake.
他们的手也会发抖.我不是要改变我的方向.我正在实现它.
I'm not changing my direction.I'm finding it.
麦琪∶这份工作比你上学还重要吗?
Maggie: This job's more important to you than school?
开萝尔∶是的,至少现在是.
Carol: Yes.Right now.
我有时会觉得如果我从哥伦比亚大学毕业后,
I mean sometimes I get the feeling that it wouldn't be me who'd be graduating
那不是我自己,而是你和爸爸.
from Columbia, it'd be you and dad.
麦琪∶哦,开萝尔.
Maggie: Oh, Carol.How can you...
你怎么可以...那好吧,不过你要答应我只再多做一个学期.
Look, just promise me that it will only be for one more semester.
开萝尔∶哦,好!一切好说!谢谢!等一下,你现在为什么这么讲理了?
Carol: Oh yeas, anything mom.Thank you.Wait, why are you being so reasonable?
麦琪∶和你爸爸结婚21年,或多或少会受点影响吧.
Maggie: Well, you can't sleep with your father for 21 years and not catch
你知道我的意思.
a little something.You know what I mean.
杰森:如果我是你的话,我会放弃.打扰,我找开萝尔西威尔.
Jason: If I were you, I'd hold off on that.Excuse me, I'm here to see Carol Seaver.
乐斯莉∶你的名字?
Leslie: Your name?
杰森∶我是她爸爸,她邀请我来吃午餐的.
Jason: I'm her father, she invited me to lunch.
开萝尔∶爸爸,你提前来了.
Carol: Dad, you're early.
杰森∶恩,我紧张的时候就会把车开的很快.
Jason: Yes, well I drive fast when I'm tense.
开萝尔∶进来,进来.我的办公室和我的...
Carol: Come in, come in.This is my office and these are all my...
杰森∶那我们要去哪里吃午餐?
Jason: So where are we going for lunch?
开萝尔∶都可以,我只是想看我是否能让你看看...
Carol: Anywhere, I just thought that if I could show you...
杰森∶开萝尔,看的什么也不能改变我的决定.
Jaosn: There's nothing you going to show me, Carol, that could change my mind.
如果这就是你为什么要请我来吃午餐的原因,那你就大错特错了.
Is that why you invited me down for lunch then you've made a big mistake.
开萝尔∶我只是想如果你来这里...
Carol: Well I just thought that if you came down here...
乐斯莉∶开萝尔,他们需要你去看看封面布局.他们说很紧急的.
Leslie: Carol, they need you in cover layout.They said it's an emergency.
开萝尔∶我不能,我...
Carol: Well I can't, I...
杰森∶去吧,去吧,我会在这里等你.
Jason: Go ahead, go, go.I'll wait here.
开萝尔∶好,我尽快回来.
Carol: Ok, I'll hurry.
杰森∶啊,嗨,是一个隔间.
Jason: Ah, hey, it's a cubicle.
瑞∶老板在吗?
Ray: Is the boss around?
杰森∶老板??
Jason: Boss?
瑞∶是的,西维尔小姐.
Ray: Yes, Ms.Seaver?
杰森∶哦!开萝尔?她刚刚出去了.
Jason: Oh, Carol?No, she just stepped out.
光线∶哦!见鬼.
Ray: Oh darn it.I need her to sign these galleys.
这些文件都等着她签名呢.我们要开始整个的印刷经营了呢.
We've got a whole press run to go.
杰森∶她马上回来,你可以把资料先留在这里.
Jason: Well she'll be back, just leave it with me.
瑞∶我可以相信你吗?
Ray: Can you be trusted?
杰森∶你觉得呢??
Jason: What do you think?
杰森∶哈罗?哦,西维尔小姐现在不在.她刚刚出去一会.
Jason: Hello?Oh, Ms.Seaver is not here right now.She stepped out for a minute.
不行,我什么事情都决定不了,我只是,
No, I can't approve anything, I'm just a, I'm her father.
我只是她的父亲.对,我很骄傲,非常骄傲.
Yes, I'm very proud, very proud.
开萝尔∶爸爸,我...
Carol: Dad, I...
杰森∶等等,等等,她回来了.听起来好像很重要.
Jason: Oh hold on, hold here she comes.Sounds very important.
开萝尔∶你好?不行,我今天就要用.
Carol: Yes?No, I need it today.No it must be today.
不行,一定要今天.就算加班我也会签字的,
I'll sign off any overtime but I want to see it on my desk by the
但是,今天结束前你必须把它放在我的桌子上.再见.
end of the day.Bye.
开萝尔∶爸爸,我知道我不能改变你的决定,
Carol: Look, dad, I know I'm not going to change your mind,
但是我也不想和你在这里争吵.
I really don't want to get into an argument here.
杰森∶你是老板.
Jason: You're the boss.
开萝尔∶是的.
Carol: Yeah.
杰森∶我的小女孩,真是难以想像.
Jason: My little girl, imagine that.
开萝尔∶爸爸,我不明白.
Carol: Dad, I'm not following.
杰森∶这不是一份愚蠢的工作,开萝尔.
Jason: This isn't a goofy job, Carol.
开萝尔∶你要喝水吗?
Carol: Do you want some water?
杰森∶你有自己的隔间,不,应该说你有自己的办公室,
Jason: You got your own cubicle here.
你有真正的安排,有家具,有人进来请你解决问题.
No, you got an office, you got real plans, you got furniture,
我觉得这里很好.我是说,我们,你和我,
you got people come in and asking you to solve problems.
我们,你,你.
I'm doing alright here.I mean, we are, you and I, we are.You, you.
开萝尔∶什么意思?
Carol: What are you saying?
杰森∶我说我为你而骄傲.
Jason: I'm saying I'm so proud of you.
开萝尔∶那我不用辞职了?
Carol: So I don't have to quit?
杰森∶不需要了...宝贝,我从来都不想强迫你.也许.
Jason: You don't have...come on, oh, honey I was never going to force you.Maybe.
开萝尔∶哦,爸爸,我什么时候让你失望过?
Carol: Oh, daddy, have I ever let you down?
杰森∶没有,没有.我多么希望我也能问和你一样的问题.
Jason: No, no.I wish I could ask you the same question.
开萝尔∶谢谢你,爸爸.
Carol: Oh daddy, thank you.
我保证下个秋季学期我会成为哥伦比亚新生的一员,就像你期待的那样.
And I promise next fall I'll be a freshman at Columbia just like you wanted.
杰森∶不,你不用.
Jason: No, you won't.
开萝尔∶什么?
Carol: What?
杰森∶不,我希望你到你想去的地方.但是我希望是哥伦比亚大学.
Jason: No. I want you to go where you want to go. But I hope it's Columbia.
开萝尔∶成交.
Carol: Deal.
杰森∶让我们吃中餐.
Jason: Let's have lunch.
开萝尔∶好.
杰森∶我正在买呢.你是想把我女儿的名字贴在门上,还是坐下来慢慢的吃你的意大利腊肠?
00:22:28,900
Carol: Ok. Jason: Come on, I'm buying. Are you going to get my daughter's name on this door or are you going to sit here and gnaw on your salami?